How should a personal trainer be utilizing
AI at the moment?
Well, let's break this down.
Most coaches watching this should have an
offline
business and an online business.
Across the both, probably with doing your
programming. So for instance,
you're going to write a phase one for a
client.
You might say to AI,
"Here's 10 clients' programs
that I've got.
What would you do to move them into phase
two?" You could then teach your AI where
you might say, "Hey,
we're going from an accumulation phase,
more reps, into
building intensity, where reps
is going to come down,
but the weight they're going
to lift is going to go up." You could
train that AI over time to help you with
your
program.
You could also keep a chat log of all the
conversations you're having with
clients, their feedback of the program.
"Hey,
riff at elevated split squats didn't feel
right.
Really struggling with this." You could
then input that into AI to make the
programs how you'd want.
You would then just sign off the programs
to
make sure it's correct. This
is probably what most platforms
and coaches are doing
anyway. Remember,
you're not paying a PT for a program,
you're paying to have it
implemented. Another question
that people have, not related to AI:
how much
information should I give away for free,
and how much should I save for my paid
program? What you should actually do
is give everything you know away for free,
like I'm doing now.
The reason you will pay me
is to make sure you actually do it.
You're not paying me for information,
the intent's for it.
The reason that people pay me is so
that I make sure they actually do it.
Once you give me three grand,
you're going to be posting more,
you're going to
build a landing page,
and you're going to start email marketing.
Otherwise,
it's going to be a waste of money.
I don't think we're there yet,
but I think AI is going to come along
really soon,
operate your calendar, diary,
keep everything in person, up to date.
And I'd say the main place you want to be
using AI for your online stuff is
ideation. On the drive back from the gym,
hit the voice button on your AI, whether
it's Claude, ChatGPT, whatever.
Tell them all of the problems
that your clients
face today,
all the things you helped them with,
all of the things that people are
struggling with, and then say,
"Give me some ideas of videos
that I should make for
tomorrow." That's a snapshot of how I
would use AI as an online coach in a
business. If you comment the word AI,
I can give you a prompt that we're using
right now in the business mentorship,
which is helping people increase their
conversions on their landing page.
Bye-bye.